## Kayvan Kazeminejad



### **Profile Summary**

I am an experienced *developer* and *architect* with over 25+ years of experience in a variety of platforms and programming languages including:

Haskell, Rust, PureScript, Scala, NixOS, Plutus, Solidity, C/C++. I have worked in a number of industries including: Blockchain, Banking and Finance, Healthcare, Music and Video streaming, Entertainment, IoT, Hardware manufacturing, and Military.

Haskell is my favorite programming language and I truly enjoy working on Haskell projects.

#### Contact details

- @ kayvan@q2io.com
- ₱ +1 415 636 1124
- kayvank
- in kayvankazeminejad

#### Personal information

Citizenship: USA

Family: Married with children Languages: English, Farsi

#### Skills

- Haskell, Rust, PureScript, NixOS, Scala,
- Kubernetes, Helm charts, AWS, GCP, Terraform
- PostgreSQL, Redshift, Big Query, MongoDB, Redis, Apache Spark, Flink, Elasticsearch
- JavaScript, Node.js, GitHub

## EXPERIENCE

#### HASKELL DEVELOPER at IOHK (Remote)

2023.09-Present

- ♦ Design and implementation of Marconi chain-indexer tool, while working with the PlutusApps team. The tool was used by a number of IOHK teams, reducing their development time significantly.
- ♦ Redesigned and upgrade Partner-Chain's Trustless Haskell, PureScript and Plutus smart contracts, allowing for seamless integration with non-IOHK blockchains
- $\diamond$  Haskell and Plutus contribution in design and implementations of StableCoin while working with dJed team, which allowed for early release of the StableCoin Pricing-Oracle
- $\diamond$  Contributed to design and implementation of the fastBft Consensus Rust platform while working with Innovations team, which lead to adaption of fastBft by the midnight blockchain

## Haskell Developer at Soostone (Remote). 2021.03–2023.09

- ♦ Contributed to the development of the napkin, A sophisticated SQL metaprogramming environment that accelerates modern data engineering efforts across multiple backends (w.g. BigQuery and Redshift
- $\diamond$  Design and implementation of the OAuth 2.0 flow for the "napkin" project, resulting in a much smoother user experience
- $\diamond$  Contribute to replacing the legacy Monad stack with a Polysemy effect system, resulting in a more maintainable and flexible architecture, hence reducing time to market

#### SENIOR CONSULTANT at *Trucklabs* (*Remote*). 2020.03–2021.02

- ♦ Built the backend portion for IoT event collection into AWS DynamoDB
- $\diamond$  Architected and developed multiple user-facing APIs including smart-trucks routing, fuel consumption, and ETA estimation. These contribution resulted in 11% fuel consumption reduction and increased driver retention by 27%
- ♦ Scala, Apache Flink, Apache Spark, ElasticSearch, Redshift, DynamoDB, Node.js

### SENIOR CONSULTANT at RChain (Remote). 2018.04–2020.03

- $\diamond$  Design and developed rSong, an on-chain music dApp that was showcased at MIT-Media-Lab as well as RCon3, the dApp was downloaded several thousand time
- $\diamond$  Contribute to design and implementation of rSpace, a Scala implementation of Tuple-Space used for RHolang smart-contracts storage layer
- ♦ Scala, Node.js, Python, RHolang smart-contracts, Kubernetes, Helm charts

#### SENIOR CONSULTANT at Vevo (San Francisco, CA). 2015.11–2018.04

- $\diamond$  Build cloud-based data services enabling Vevo's music recommendation engine to improved user-retention by 17%
- ♦ Build HTTP APIs and a number of JSON-RPC services using Http4s, providing data-services to downstream teams as well Vevo clients
- ♦ Mentor junior developers
- ♦ Scala, Node.js, Python, Kubernetes, Helm charts, Terraform, AWS Serverless

## SENIOR CONSULTANT at Intel(Santa Clara, CA). 2013.09–2015.11

- $\diamond$  Contribute to design and implementation of VoD, Video on Demand, automated workflow for video assets encoding/decoding clusters, resulting in decreased video dissemination time by 39%
- $\diamond$  Contributed to design and implementation of VoD encoder/decoder of video assets in C++ to take advantage of the new clusters, decreasing decoding time by 37%
- $\diamond$  Deign and implementation of the VoD reporting system providing real-time status-reporting of transcoders pipeline
- $\diamond$  Scala, C++, Terraform, MongoDB, Cassandra, ElasticSearch, Kafka

## Consultant at Various locations

2000-01-2013.09

I worked as a consultant in various industries including, Banking, Finance, Healthcare, Defense, Hardware manufacturing, and Government

Kayvan	Kazem	nineiad	
rtayvan	Muzcii	micjau	

# Curriculum Vitae

# EDUCATION

California State University, Sacramento.
Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Mathematics

1994–1999

# Certi<u>fications</u>

- ♦ Data Base Adminstation *Northrop Grumman*
- ♦ NETWORK ADMINSTATION, Northrop Grumman.
- ♦ Advance Network Programming, Northrop Grumman.
- ♦ GAME THEORY, Coursera.
- ♦ CRYPTOGRAPHY, Coursera.
- ♦ SOLIDITY, *Alchemy*.

## HOBBIES

I am an Endurance Athlete, and have completed several IRONMAN